<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>flofriday</title>
    <link>http://flofriday.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on flofriday</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 10:07:26 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://flofriday.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Write a simple Web Search Engine</title>
      <link>http://flofriday.github.io/posts/write-a-simple-web-search-engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 10:07:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://flofriday.github.io/posts/write-a-simple-web-search-engine/</guid>
      <description>A Web Search Engine consists basically of two parts, a crawler that downloads Websites and builds an index on their words, and an application to use for the endusers (usually a webserver) with an query-engine that uses the index created by the crawler.
In this post we will write a very simple crawler and a minimal webserver that allows the user to find all websites in the index that contain a (single word) searchterm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s build a bad Web Search - Part 1</title>
      <link>http://flofriday.github.io/posts/lets-build-a-bad-web-search-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 09:21:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://flofriday.github.io/posts/lets-build-a-bad-web-search-part-1/</guid>
      <description>In this series we explore how a simple Web Search works (like Google in the 90s). We will use Golang to build the backend, however I will not use too specific Go features or packages and it should be easy to follow along with any other language.
Extracting Text To create an search-index we first need pure text-file which means we need to extract the text from an HTML file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About flofriday</title>
      <link>http://flofriday.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://flofriday.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is flofriday and I am a Computerscience student at TU Wien (Austria). Interested in all things related to computers from webservers over games to simple scripts. Currently learning about searchengines (like Google)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
